We're with you!
我们会追随你
Let's go!
冲啊
There are about 350 people.
大概有350人
Out of which only about 100 actually know how to fight.
其中大概只有一百人知道如何作战
Get an exact number later on.
等一下帮我确定人数
Are we seriously going to do this, Boss?
老大 我们真的要这么做吗?
The master is bent on doing it.
主人执意这么做
We have no choice.
我们别无选择
They must be insane.
他们一定是疯了
Do these guys think they have a chance against the king's army?
这些人认为 他们有机会打赢国王的军队?
All of them owe the master money.
他们全都欠了主人的钱
He assembled them by saying that he'll write it off if they fight.
主人打着参战抵债的口号 将他们召集起来
Even still, they wouldn't have come if they knew their enemy was the king.
尽管如此 如果他们知道 敌人是国王 他们就不会来了
But now that they're here, they can't turn back
但他们现在既然来了 也无法回头了
because their pride as a Nordic man won't allow that.
因为他们身为北方人的尊严 不允许他们这么做
And plus, people feel invincible in big numbers.
况且 人数众多 就会让人感到坚不可摧
It makes you feel like you can win.
让人觉得一定会打赢
It was a smart tactic to wait until everyone assembled
等到召集众人前来之后 才宣布敌人是国王
before saying our enemy is the king.
这招挺聪明的
I didn't know Thorgil was this battlewise.
我不知道托尔吉尔原来这么足智多谋
The master is determined to do it. He's already got an army.
主人已下定决心 他已经集结了人马
This place is going to become a battlefield.
这个地方即将成为战场
I told you, didn't I? We have to leave this farm now
我早说过 对吧? 我们得立刻离开这里
or we'll get caught up in it, Thorfinn.
不然我们就会被卷入这件事 托尔芬
I know, but...
我知道 但是...
Leif,
雷夫
we cannot leave Arnheid like this
我们不能放下阿奴纳不管
and escape from the farm.
就这样逃离这座农场
Thank you so much
非常感谢你
for caring about someone like me.
这么关心像我这样的人
You've changed, Thorfinn.
你变了 托尔芬
At first, when I saw you, I thought you were the wrong person.
我看到你的第一眼 还以为又找错人了
You look much better now, Thorfinn.
托尔芬 你现在看起来好多了
I finally got to see you again. I can't just
我终于又再见到你了
leave you and escape on my own.
我不能放下你不管 就这样一走了之
Pater, there it is again!
帕特 又来了
Turn her to the side.
帮她翻身
We can't let her choke on whatever she's coughing up.
我们不能让她 被自己咳出来的东西噎到
Pater,
帕特
is it possible to relocate Arnheid?
有可能把阿奴纳抬到另一个地方吗?
No, I think we should be careful right now.
不行 我认为现在必须非常小心
Once she wakes up, I can see how she's doing,
一旦她醒来 我就能知道她现在的状况
but at the moment
但此时此刻
I honestly can't determine her condition.
我真的无法判断她的病情
And plus, I'm worried about her baby.
况且 我也很担心她的宝宝
The best thing we can do is let her rest.
最好的做法就是让她休息
At least until she regains consciousness.
至少等到她恢复意识
One day...
一天...
Let's wait for just one day and see how it goes.
我们等个一天吧 到时候再看看
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗?
What are you going to do after that?
你之后有何打算?
Boss, hurry!
老大 快点
- Are they here? - Yes.
-他们到了吗? -是的
Where I'm pointing.
我手指的那个方向
That was faster than I expected.
比我预期得更快
Send a message to the master! We spot a fleet in the north.
带个讯息给主人 我们在北方发现一支舰队
The king's army is here.
国王的大军即将抵达
- They're here. - That's them.
-他们来了 -是他们
- What should we do? - First...
-我们该怎么办? -首先...
You idiot! Don't shoot without permission!
你这个白痴 没得到允许 不得出箭
Obviously it won't reach at this distance!
这种距离怎么可能射得到?
Lure them in more and then at once--
引诱他们靠得再近一点然后一举...
Damn it! Go back!
该死 撤退
Darn it!
该死
How are they reaching all the way here?
距离这么远 他们怎么射得过来?
Spread out and gain control over the area.
散开 拿到这个区域的控制权
Make way for His Majesty The King.
替国王陛下开路
It seems as though Ketil wants to fight me.
看来凯特尔似乎想和我一较高下
Dispatch an envoy, Wulf.
派使者过去 沃尔夫
We will line up here and wait for Ketil's response.
我们部署在这里 等待凯特尔的回复
Yes, Your Majesty.
遵命 陛下
This is a nice piece of land. It's a waste to stain it with blood.
这块地真的很不错 让它被血染实在太可惜了
Based on the aforementioned reasons, King Canute
基于上述原因 库奴特王
has ordered to have the rebellious Ketil and his family
下令反叛者凯特尔和他的家人
be outlawed for ten years from this day forward.
流放十年 从今日开始生效
Under normal circumstances, these crimes are worthy of death,
在一般状况之下 这等罪行只有唯一死刑
but the lives of Ketil and his family are spared
但凯特尔和他的家人得以免于一死
as a result of the mercy of none other than His Majesty.
是伟大的陛下网开一面
Humbly accept your punishment.
你们就俯首认罪吧
That is all.
公布完毕
If you don't want to die, hurry up and flee to another country.
如果你们想活命 就赶快逃到另一个国家吧
We will wait until tomorrow morning for your answer.
我们等着明天一早听到你们的回复
You're useless!
你们这群废物
How could you let them on shore so easily!
让他们不费吹灰之力就登陆成功
Rebellion? Outlawry?
造反?流放?
Don't get cocky with me, you brat!
你这个小鬼 少在我面前放肆
I'm back.
我回来了
Thorgil! How was Canute's army?
托尔吉尔 库奴特的军队目前状况如何?
They were boiling their pots and leisurely eating lunch.
他们正在烧水做饭 悠悠哉哉地享用午餐
There are two warships and two cargo ships.
他们有两艘战舰 两艘货船
And they've pitched tents right by the landing place.
他们也在登陆点搭起了营帐
They have approximately 100 men.
大约有一百人
One hundred?
一百人?
Yeah, excluding the slaves and servants.
对 不包括奴隶和仆人
- What a joke. - Did you hear that?
-开什么玩笑? -你听见了吗?
That is less than a third of our army.
还不到我们的三分之一
That darn Canute... Did he think that we would
那该死的库奴特 他真的以为我们见到国王本尊
bow down in fear once we saw the king himself?
就会吓得屁滚尿流 立刻投降吗?
This land is home to countless daredevils who aren't afraid of the king!
这片土地属于一群不怕死的人 国王有什么好怕的?
Let's go, all of you!
大家听好 我们冲
Whoever beheads the king will receive a prize of their choice!
砍下国王脑袋的人 想要什么样的奖赏 我都会满足他
Yeah!
好!
Yes!
好
What a happy bunch.
这群人还真开心啊
These 100 men aren't ordinary warriors.
这一百人可不是一般的战士
The ones surrounding the large tent...
在大营帐周围的那群人...
Those are the king's thegns.
他们是国王的臣子
Th... The king is seriously here?
国王真的来了?
We're talking about the royal guard here.
我们说的可是皇家警卫啊
They're a group of the strongest warriors in Denmark.
他们是由丹麦最强的战士所组成
And they're Thorgil's former brothers-in-arms.
而且他们是托尔吉尔之前的战友
S... So you mean...
所以你的意思是...
all of them are as strong as Thorgil?
他们全都跟托尔吉尔一样强?
So what about the other guys in white capes?
那些穿白胞又是什么人?
Are they weaker compared to the royal guard?
跟皇家警卫比起来 他们更弱吗?
What? You've never seen them before?
什么?你从没见过那一群人吗?
They are the Jomsvikings.
他们是约姆战士
I've never seen your eyes open so wide.
我从没看你这么大惊失色过
We can't win.
我们赢不了的
They're on another level compared to our hodgepodge of farmers and warriors.
我们这群差劲的农夫和战士 根本不是他们的对手
They're the kind of people who only think about war,
他们那种人 从早到晚
from morning to night.
满脑子想的都是战争
But it seems like the master needs to fight them once to understand that.
但看来主人似乎得与他们交过手 才能明白这一点
If you want to run away, go ahead.
如果你们想逃走的话 请便
King Canute is giving us time to escape.
库奴特王给了我们逃跑的时间
What are you going to do, Boss?
老大 你打算怎么做?
I'm a commander. How could I run away?
我是指挥官 我怎么能逃跑?
I'll try my best to protect as many as I can
我会尽最大的努力保护
of those 350 overconfident dummies.
那350名不知天高地厚的蠢蛋
Well then,
那么
why don't we tie up the Ketil family and hand them over?
我们何不制伏凯特尔一家人 将他们交给国王呢?
That's right! Then we won't have to go to war.
没错 那我们就不用参战了
We're going to tie up Thorgil too?
我们也得制伏托尔吉尔吗?
Don't be a chicken! If eight of us go, we can manage.
别那么孬种 我们八人合力 一定能搞定的
No, it's not just Thorgil.
不 不只是托尔吉尔
There's the rumored "Iron Fist Ketil."
还有传闻中的“铁拳凯特尔”
You know the story about how he killed a bear with his bare hands.
你们知道他徒手 宰了一头熊的故事吧?
Come on, let's just run away, Boss!
走吧 我们干脆一走了之吧 老大
Nothing good is going to come from being stubborn.
固执不会给我们带来任何好处
"Iron Fist," huh?
“铁拳”是吗?
I know Iron Fist very well.
我跟铁拳很熟
I met him when I was about 15 or 16.
我在15、16岁的时候见过他
He showed me the ropes on the battlefield.
他教了我各种战场上的事
He really was incredibly strong.
他确实是无比神勇
He's like an older brother to me.
对我而言 他就像个大哥哥
I forget how many years ago it was, but I got into a little trouble
我不太记得是在几年前了 那时我惹了一些麻烦
and I became a fugitive.
后来成了逃犯
I thought my big brother, Ketil, would be willing to take me in,
我心想 我的大哥凯特尔 应该会愿意收留我
so I followed the rumors and fled to this farm.
所以我跟随着传闻 逃到这座农场
However,
然而
when I finally arrived here...
当我终于抵达这里时
Who are you? Do you have business with me?
你哪位?你找我有事吗?
It was a completely different person, believe it or not.
信不信由你 他完全变了一个人
Huh?
什么?
What?
是喔?
What in the world!
搞什么啊?
The master is deceiving everyone.
主人骗了大家
Just because they happened to have the same name.
只因为他们刚好同名同姓
I'm speechless.
我真是哑口无言
How did no one find out until now?
为什么至今都没有人发现这件事?
But it's not like I had anywhere else to go.
但我在当时也已经走投无路
So I ended up working here as a guard dog.
所以最后我留了下来 成了一条看门狗
They've fed me for free for quite some time.
他们免费提供食物给我 也好一段时间了
It's about time I pay them back for the food.
到了我回报他们的时候了
Well, you guys can do whatever you like.
你们想怎么做都可以
Now you know the master is a fraud
你们现在知道主人是个骗子了
who isn't worth risking your life for.
不值得你们为他冒生命危险
Well then, take care.
那么 你们保重
Don't try to act cool, you idiots.
别耍帅了 你们这些白痴
You guys will die before you get to pay back for your meals.
你们根本还来不及 回报温饱之恩就会翘辫子啦
Sh... Shut up!
闭嘴
If we dine and dash against a fraud like him,
如果我们在这个骗子的农场白吃白喝
that will make us the real scum of the earth.
我们就会成为世界上最无耻的无赖
We will work and pay for our food!
我们会用劳动换取食物
Don't go blabbering about what I just told you.
就别喋喋不休地重复我说过的话了
Their backs are against the ocean.
他们背对着海
The king's army is positioned in two lines here.
国王的军队已部署成两条战线
This circle is King Canute.
这个圆圈是库奴特王
They've docked their ships on the sand
他们把船停靠在沙滩上
and are not thinking about what's behind them.
完全不操心后方的状况
They know that we don't have a sufficient army.
他们知道我们的兵力不足
The terrain is wide open so we can't launch a surprise attack.
原野十分平坦辽阔 我们也无法发动奇袭
Olmar, how would you attack them?
欧玛 你会怎么进攻?
Huh?
什么?
A night attack?
夜袭?
Wrong.
错了
Night attacks are done by first-rate warriors.
夜袭只有一流的战士才做得到
It's impossible for amateurs.
业余人士是不可能的
Those guys won't be of any help.
那些家伙起不了什么作用
By the time you count to 100 they'll all be killed.
你从一数到一百时 他们也全死了
What?
什么?
Then why did you assemble them?
那你干嘛还要召集他们?
You amateur.
你这个业余人士
There's only one reason.
只有一个理由
So they can distract the king
在我们从一数到一百的时候
while we count to 100.
他们会引开国王的注意力
Thorgil! Where are you, Thorgil?
托尔吉尔 你人呢?托尔吉尔
Jeez, where is he when I need him?
天啊 我需要他的时候 他人呢?
Master, the entire army is ready.
主人 所有兵力已整军完成
All right. On my order, get ready to fire.
好的 我一声令下 就准备开战
Get ready!
准备好
Master, this is the final warning.
主人 容我提醒你最后一次
If we do this, we'll lose.
如果开战 我们会输
That's enough, Snake.
够了 蛇
I am the Iron Fist Ketil.
我是铁拳凯特尔
Nothing about me is inferior to that brat.
我完全不输那个自以为是的小鬼
Fire!
发射
It's begun.
开战了
The best of luck, Pater.
祝你好运 帕特
Damn it!
该死
It's all right. Let's go.
可以了 走吧
Both armies are in the middle of fighting.
两边打起来了
Slowly! Try to keep it stable.
慢一点 尽量不要造成颠簸
I'm not going to be responsible for this...
我可不打算为这件事负责...
This is stealing, isn't it?
这是偷窃 对吧?
Stealing a slave...
偷了一名奴隶
Don't worry about it.
别担心这个了
I left a reasonable amount of money.
我留下了一笔合适的钱
I didn't know you had it in you, Dad.
我不知道你这么有胆识 爸
She's Thorfinn's friend. I can't leave her behind.
她是托尔芬的朋友 我不能弃她于不顾
If she stays here, she will be killed.
如果她留下来的话 会必死无疑
We couldn't
我们无法...
say goodbye to the old master.
向老主人道别了啊
Did the children fall asleep?
孩子们睡着了吗?
Yes.
是的
They fall asleep so quickly when they're swayed by the wagon.
在摇晃的马车上 他们很快就睡着了
Are you scared?
你害怕吗?
Don't worry.
别担心
We'll get out of this dark forest soon.
我们很快就会走出这片黑暗的森林
This place is a pool of pain and despair.
这个地方充满痛苦和绝望
It's a forest with bloodthirsty beasts.
这座森林里有嗜血的野兽
It's not the place to raise a life.
不适合抚养孩子
We have a warm home waiting for us.
有个温暖的家在等着我们
It was a long, painful journey, wasn't it?
这是一段漫长而艰辛的旅程吧?
But that pain will soon end.
但苦难很快就会结束
Yes.
对
I guess you're right.
我想你说得对
But even then,
但就算是这样
there are still...
这里仍然...
beings who try to survive out here.
有生命会想尽办法存活下来
Gardar?
哥达?
Go ahead
你去吧
and say goodbye to those who took care of you.
去向那些照顾过你的人道别吧
I'll be waiting here with the children.
我和孩子们会在这里等你
You're right.
你说得对
I have to say thank you to Einar and everybody.
我得向埃纳尔和其他人说声谢谢
Stop! Stop!
停下来...
It's me! Can you comprehend?
是我 你认得出我是谁吗?
How do you feel?
你感觉怎么样?
Einar...
埃纳尔
Advance 50 steps! Be thorough.
向前50步 全力冲刺
Show them the difference in power.
让他们看看双方的力量差距有多大
As expected of the Jomsvikings.
约姆战士果然名不虚传
They only have one line of 70 men,
他们一列才70个人
but they're not faltering at all.
但他们丝毫不动摇
At this point, we don't need a rear guard.
现在看来 我们并不需要在后方部署人马
Send the thegns in the second row to arrest Ketil.
发动第二横队的臣子 拿下凯特尔
Yes, Your Majesty.
遵命 陛下
Don't retreat! Charge!
别撤退 进攻
Show them your determination!
让对方瞧瞧我们的决心
Damn it!
该死
Where did my sons go?
我儿子跑哪儿去了?
It's impossible
带着剑游泳
to swim while carrying a sword.
是根本不可能的事
It's impossible, brother.
哥 这是不可能的
I can't
我没办法...
become like you.
成为跟你一样的人
You'll never see me coming, King Canute!
你绝对料不到我有这一招 库奴特王
"Pain."
第20集:痛苦
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译:朱未耒